hermanmiller.com 2019-06-18

# Privacy Policy - Herman Miller

Herman Miller respects your privacy and provides you with this privacy policy (the “Privacy Policy”), which is always available at [www.hermanmiller.com/privacy](https://www.hermanmiller.com/legal/privacy-policy/) or by contacting us at [privacyinquiry@hermanmiller.com](mailto:privacyinquiry@hermanmiller.com). The Privacy Policy describes our current privacy practices with respect to the collection and use of your personal information, and your choices with respect to our use and collection thereof. This Privacy Policy governs all visits to [hermanmiller.com](https://www.hermanmiller.com/) and its affiliated websites, however accessed, and our related mobile app (collectively, the "Site" unless otherwise noted), as well as transactions through the Site or app. Capitalized terms not defined in this Privacy Policy are set forth in the Terms of Use.

By using the Site, or sharing your contact information with us, you consent to and accept the privacy practices described in this Privacy Policy.

**GOVERNING LAW**

**CONTACT INFORMATION**

**CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY**

**INFORMATION WE COLLECT AND/OR RECEIVE**

PERSONAL INFORMATION  
GEOLOCATIONAL INFORMATION  
OTHER INFORMATION  
YOUR ACTIVITY  
YOUR DEVICE  
COOKIES AND SIMILAR TECHNOLOGY  
THIRD-PARTY ANALYTICS  

**USE AND SHARING OF INFORMATION**

USING YOUR INFORMATION  
SHARING YOUR INFORMATION  
ADVERTISING AND MARKETING  
STANDARD OPEN AUTHORIZATION AND SIMILAR TECHNOLOGY  

**ACCESS TO YOUR INFORMATION AND OPT-OUT**

****EXTERNAL WEBSITES****

**DO-NOT-TRACK**

**HOW WE PROTECT YOUR INFORMATION**  

**YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS**  

**CHILDREN'S PRIVACY**  

**FOR USERS IN THE EUROPEAN ECONOMIC AREA AND SWITZERLAND**  

**INTERNATIONAL TRANSFER OF INFORMATION COLLECTED**  

**Governing Law**  
Unless otherwise indicated herein, our USA websites are governed and operated in accordance with the laws of the United States and are intended for the use of residents of the United States.

**Contact Information**  
**Address**  
If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at:  
Herman Miller, Inc.  
Attn: Legal Department Privacy Inquiry  
855 East Main Ave.  
Zeeland, MI 49464

**Personal Data Management Contact**  
Email: [privacyinquiry@hermanmiller.com](mailto:privacyinquiry@hermanmiller.com?subject=Contact%20Us%20Form:%20Personal%20Data%20Management)  
Subject: "Contact Us Form: Personal Data Management"

**Changes to Our Privacy Policy**  
We may make changes to this policy from time to time, in our sole discretion. We will provide you notice of material changes by indicating that the Privacy Policy has been updated on our homepage and will indicate the date we made the update above. Your continued use of any of the Site after the changes have been made will constitute your acceptance of the changes. Please make sure you read any such notice carefully. If you do not wish to continue using the Site under the new version of the policy, please uninstall any mobile application and cease using the Site.

**What Information Do We Collect and/or Receive from You?**  
The information we collect from you varies, depending on the way you use our Site. We collect and/or receive information from you when using our Site in the ways described below.

**Personal Information You Provide to Us**  
When you use our Site, we collect information that you choose to share with us. We collect and receive several types of personal information from you when you use our Site. This information may include:

  * Name
  * Shipping/billing address
  * Telephone number
  * Email address
  * Credit or debit card information

If you apply for employment with us through the Site, we collect personal information such as your name, address, e-mail, and phone number. In addition, we may collect information relating to your education and employment history when you submit that information as part of an employment application. Not all requested information is required, however, and we specifically indicate what information is required to submit your employment application.

You may also log in to our employment system using a Yahoo account. If you use the option to log in with Yahoo we may receive information included in your Yahoo profile. By doing so you consent to our receiving certain personal information about you from Yahoo, in accordance with the associated terms and privacy policy of Yahoo. See the Standard Open Authorization and Similar Technology Section below for more information about logging into our services through a third-party account such as Yahoo.

**Geolocational Information**  
Certain features and functionality of the Site are based on your location. To provide these features and functionalities, if you consent, we may collect geolocational information from your mobile device, wireless carrier, and/or certain third-party service providers. Collection of such information occurs only when you are using your mobile device. You may decline to allow us to collect such information or disable location services on your mobile device but doing so will restrict certain features and functionalities to you.

**Other Information**  
In addition to the information outlined above, we may collect or receive additional information (collectively, “Other Information”). While you do not need to provide personal information to browse or use our Site, Our Site collects certain information automatically about you and your use of our Site that does not necessarily personally identify you. This Other Information includes information on how you interact with our Site and information regarding the device you use to access our Site and Services. This Other Information may include:

  * **Information from your Site activity**  
When you browse our Site, we may collect: IP address (static or dynamic); browser type and language; operating system; domain server; referring and exit pages and URLs; date and time of visit; the pages you visited while on the Site; and similar data.

  * **Information about your device**  
When interacting with our Site, we may collect information about your device including: type of computer or device; operating system and version (e.g., iOS, Android, Windows); carrier and country location; and similar data. Additional information collected from your device may include any of the following: Universally Unique ID (UUID); Advertising Identifier (IDFA); MAC address; Hardware and processor information (e.g., storage, chip speed); Network type (e.g., WiFi, 3G, 4G, LTE).

**How We Use Cookies and Similar Technology**  
We and our service partners may use cookies, web beacons, and other technologies to receive and store certain types of information whenever you interact with the Site through your computer or mobile device. Cookies are small data files that are often stored on one's computer each time one visits a new website. Cookies may store unique identifiers, user preferences and other information. We may use cookies for various purposes, including to: facilitate the sign in process to the Site; authenticate users; personalize your experience when visiting a Site; and analyze which portions of the Site are most visited or used. We use cookies to help personalize your experience when visiting the Site. These cookies also help to uniquely identify your computer for security purposes and may enable us and our third-party service providers to serve ads on our behalf across the Internet. You may opt to set your browser to refuse cookies or indicate when a cookie is being sent. For more information about how to do this, and about cookies in general, you can visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/). However, refusal of cookies may affect the experience at many third party websites, including the Site.

**Google Analytics**  
We use or may use third-party analytics services, such as Google Analytics of Facebook Pixels, to evaluate your use of the Site, compile reports on activity, collect demographic data, analyze performance metrics, and collect and evaluate other information related to the Site. Google Analytics is a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc., (“Google”). Google Analytics places cookies on your computer, to help the website analyze how users use the Site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the Site (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. Google will use this information to evaluate your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google’s behalf. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. By using this Site, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above. For more information regarding Google Analytics please visit Google's website, and pages that describe Google Analytics, such as [www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html](http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html)

**Facebook Conversion Tracking/Custom Audience**  
The Site also uses Facebook's Conversion Tracking or Custom Audience Pixel service. The service allows us to follow the actions of users after they are redirected by clicking on a Facebook advertisement. We are thus able to record the efficacy of Facebook advertisements for statistical and market research purposes. The collected data is saved and processed by Facebook. Facebook may connect the data with your Facebook account and use the data for their own advertising purposes. For more information regarding Facebook Conversion Tracking, please visit Facebook’s website, and pages that describe Facebook Conversion Tracking and Custom Audience Pixels, such as [www.facebook.com/about/privacy/](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/) and www.facebook.com/ads/preferences, where you can also revoke permission for this service.

**How Do We Use Your Information?**  
We use your information to provide, analyze, administer, enhance, and personalize our Site and services we provide to you, including marketing our services to you. We also use your information to communicate with you and to operate our business. More specifically, we may use your information to:  

  * Deliver our products and services to you, including confirming and tracking your orders
  * Communicate with you about your orders or inquiries
  * Provide you updates, reminders, or other information about products and services you have ordered or that may interest you
  * Analyze and improve our Site or products and/or services
  * Personalize your Site experience
  * Administer our contests, sweepstakes, rewards, and other promotional programs
  * Inform you about new and existing products, services, and other offers and information about Herman Miller and its various brands that we think may interest you
  * Consider you for employment
  * Prevent, detect, investigate, or remediate security or other legal concerns, including fraud
  * Protect the rights, property, or safety of Herman Miller or our other users, or any other person or the copyright-protected content of the Site
  * Comply with applicable laws, regulations or industry requirements, or respond to subpoenas or government requests
  * Fulfill any other purpose for which you provide it or consent 

**How Do We Share Your Information?**  
We may share information collected about you in the following situations:  

  * **Service Providers**  
We may share your information with service providers to perform functions and services on our behalf to deliver our products or services and/or to conduct our business. These include product delivery services, payment processors, data hosting and storage providers, customer service, marketing, and data analytics service providers. We only share information with our service providers to the extent necessary for them to fulfill their obligations and solely with respect to the reason they were retained by us.
  * **Related Companies**  
We may share some or all of your information with any of our parent companies, subsidiaries, joint ventures, or other companies under common control with us.
  * **Corporate Changes**  
We might buy or sell businesses or assets. In the event of a corporate sale, merger, reorganization, sale of assets, dissolution, or similar event, the information may be part of the transferred assets.
  * **For Legal or Security Reasons**  
We may disclose information to others if we are required to do so by law, or whenever we believe that disclosing such information is necessary or advisable to protect and defend our rights, property or the safety of us or others. Note that we may be required to disclose an individual’s personal information in response to a lawful request by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. We may also disclose your information to detect and/or resolve any fraud or security concerns.
  * **Employment**  
We may share your information in connection with an employment application to verify the information you provide.
  * **Consent**  
We may share your information in accordance with any consent to use or share your information that you provide us.  

Other than expressly identified herein, we do not share your personal information with non-affiliated third parties for their marketing purposes.

**Interest Based Advertising**  
We belong to ad networks that may use your browsing history across participating websites to show you interest-based advertisements on those websites. To learn more about interest-based advertisements and your opt-out rights and options, visit the Digital Advertising Alliance [www.aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/) and the Network Advertising Initiative [www.networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/). Please note that if you choose to opt out, you will continue to see ads on our Site, but they will not be based on how you browse and shop.

**Standard Open Authorization and Similar Technology (“OAuth”)**  
With your permission, in addition to the uses of or access to your Personal Information discussed above, third-party applications and services may access your personal information using OAuth if you choose to log into our Site using your log-in information from those third-party applications. We may also use OAuth to allow us to share information about you that is stored by us without sharing your security credentials.

**Your Access and Choices About Your Information**  
You can access and update most of your account information on our Site by logging into your account. If you want to access, update, or delete other personal information that we may have, please exercise your rights here: [Data Subject Access Request](https://app.onetrust.com/app/#/webform/4b13d068-2f48-4a4f-86c4-10945a1896a0). To protect your privacy, before we give you access to or let you update your information, we may ask you to verify your identity or provide additional information. We will try to update and allow you to access your information for free, but if it would require a disproportionate effort on our part, we may charge a fee. We will disclose any such fee before we comply with your request. We may reject a request for a number of reasons, including, for example, that the request risks the privacy of other users, requires technical efforts that are disproportionate to the request, is repetitive, or is unlawful.

You may opt-out of receiving certain future email communications from us, by clicking on the unsubscribe link at the bottom of emails you receive from us. You may also contact us at the email provided in this Privacy Policy. We will use commercially reasonable efforts to process such requests in a timely manner. You cannot opt out of receiving transactional emails or communications related to your account with us.

**Third-Party Websites**  
We are not responsible for the practices employed by third-party websites or services linked to or from our Site, including the information or content contained in such websites or services, and this Privacy Policy does not apply to them. Privacy policies on such linked websites may be different from our Privacy Policy. Your browsing and interaction with any third-party website or service, including those that have a link on our Site, are subject to that third party’s own rules and privacy policies. You access such linked websites at your own risk. You should always read the privacy policy of a linked website before disclosing any of your information on such website.

**Do Not Track**  
Our Site does not currently support Do Not Track. Our Site does not respond if your browser sends a “do not track” signal or similar mechanism to indicate you do not wish to be tracked or receive interest-based ads.

**How We Protect Your Information**  
We use reasonable physical, technical and administrative security measures and safeguards to protect the confidentiality and security of your personal information. However, since the Internet is not a 100% secure environment and no security system or measures are impenetrable, we cannot guarantee, ensure, or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us. There is no guarantee that information may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach of any of our physical, technical, or managerial safeguards. It is your responsibility to protect the security of your login information. Please note that e-mails and other communications you send to us through our Site are not encrypted, and we strongly advise you not to communicate any confidential information through these means. You should secure your password and not share it with any other individual. Be careful when using your login information on or making purchases from public computers. Always log off when finished.

**Your California Privacy Rights**  
Under California’s "Shine the Light" law, Civil Code Section 1798.83, California residents who provide personal information in obtaining products or services for personal, family or household use are entitled to request and obtain once a calendar year information about the customer information shared, if any, with other businesses for their own direct marketing uses. As set forth in this Privacy Policy, we do not share customer information with third parties for their own direct marketing uses.

**Children’s Privacy**  
The Site is not directed or targeted towards, nor intended for use by, persons under the age of 13. If you are not at least 13 years of age, do not access, use, or register on the Site. We do not knowingly collect Personal Information from persons under age 13 (in which case we will terminate and delete your account and all information contained therein) without prior parental consent.

**FOR USERS IN THE EUROPEAN ECONOMIC AREA AND SWITZERLAND**

**General Data Protection Regulations (GDPR) Information**  
For more information about Herman Miller’s privacy practices with respect to personal data collected in the EEA and Switzerland, please refer to our privacy policies for those jurisdictions: [www.hermaniller.com/en_gb/privacy](https://www.hermanmiller.com/en_gb/legal/privacy-policy/).

**Herman Miller as Controller**  
Herman Miller obtains and processes personal information in different capacities. When you provide us with your information through our Site or to use our Services, we serve as a data controller. When we act as a data controller we determine how personal information will be utilized, in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

**Our Legal Basis for Processing Your Personal Data**  
We process the personal information you provide relating to the services and Site to perform our contractual obligations to provide you products and services. We also process your personal information based on our legitimate interests to provide our products and services and Site to you, to develop and improve our products and services and Site that we provide to you, to prevent fraud, and/or comply with law enforcement requests. Where we ask for consent, we process certain personal information based on your consent.

**Data Subject Rights Access and Control of Your Information**  
We enable you to have control over the accuracy of your personal information. You can access and review your personal information by logging into the Site and visiting your account profile page. You can also exercise your data rights here: [Data Subject Access Request](https://app.onetrust.com/app/#/webform/4b13d068-2f48-4a4f-86c4-10945a1896a0). To protect your privacy, before we give you access to or let you update your information, we may ask you to verify your identity or provide additional information. We will try to update and allow you to access your information for free, but if it would require a disproportionate effort on our part, we may charge a fee. We will disclose the fee before we comply with your request. We may reject a request for any of a number of reasons, including, for example, that the request risks the privacy of other users, requires technical efforts that are disproportionate to the request, is repetitive, or is unlawful.

**Right to Rectification**  
You have the right to correct your personal data if incorrect, which also includes the right to have incomplete personal data completed. You can do so by logging into your account and deactivating any incorrect or incomplete information and adding the corrected and/or completed information. You can also exercise your data rights here: [Data Subject Access Request](https://app.onetrust.com/app/#/webform/4b13d068-2f48-4a4f-86c4-10945a1896a0).

**Data Portability**  
When we process your personal data by automated means that you have provided to us based on consent or through a contract, you have the right to get a copy of that data in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and have that transferred to you or to third party.

**Right to Restriction of Processing**  
You have the right to request that we restrict the processing of your personal information:

  * During the pending period of time where we verify the accuracy of any personal data that you claim is inaccurate
  * Where the processing of your personal data is unlawful but you oppose erasure and instead request that we restrict the use of your personal data
  * If we no longer need your personal data but it is required for you to make or defend legal claims
  * During the pending period of time where we verify our legitimate interest to process your data when you object to such processing

**Erasure of Personal Data**  
You have the right to delete the data collected through our Site and can do so by logging into your account and either deleting your account or deleting the specific personal data. There may be instances where we may not be able to delete your data or where we retain a copy of your data, for example, where we may need it to comply with a legal obligation or to protect the rights of others.

**How Long We Keep Your Personal Data**  
We retain your personal data for as long as necessary to provide the products, services and Site to you. We will retain and use this information as long as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements, and then we will delete it.

**How to Exercise Your Rights**  
In order to exercise the rights stated above, please visit: [Data Subject Access Request](https://app.onetrust.com/app/#/webform/4b13d068-2f48-4a4f-86c4-10945a1896a0). You can also exercise many of your data rights through your account.

**Right to Complain to Supervisory Authority**  
If you believe that Herman Miller is processing your personal data in an incorrect or unlawful manner, please exercise your data rights here: [Data Subject Access Request](https://app.onetrust.com/app/#/webform/4b13d068-2f48-4a4f-86c4-10945a1896a0). For those located in the European Union, you also have a right to file a complaint with a Supervisory Authority in the EU.

**INTERNATIONAL TRANSFER OF INFORMATION COLLECTED**  
Information Herman Miller collects from you will be stored and processed in the United States. If you provide us information, it will be transferred to, processed, and accessed in the United States.

**EU-US Privacy Shield**  
We comply with the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the US Department of Commerce (the "privacy Shield") regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries. Herman Miller has certified that it adheres to the Privacy Shield principles of: notice; choice; accountability for onward transfer; security; data, integrity and purpose limitation; access; and recourse, enforcement and liability. If there is any conflict between the policies in this Privacy Policy and Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield, and to view our certification page when available, please visit: [https://www.privacyshield.gov](https://www.privacyshield.gov/). Herman Miller is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission (“FTC”).

**Resolution of Complaints**  
In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, Herman Miller commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. European Union citizens with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy should first contact Herman Miller at [privacyinquiry@hermanmiller.com](mailto:privacyinquiry@hermanmiller.com). Herman Miller has further committed to:

For Non-Human Resources Data, refer unresolved complaints to the EU-US Privacy Shield Principles BBB EU PRIVACY SHIELD, a non-profit alternative dispute resolution provider located in the United States and operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed, please visit [www.bbb.org/EU-privacy-shield/for-eu-consumers/](http://www.bbb.org/EU-privacy-shield/for-eu-consumers/)for more information and to file a complaint.

For Human Resources Data, we have committed to participate in the dispute resolution procedures of the EU Data Protection Authorities (DPA’s). For information on how to contact your jurisdiction’s DPA, visit <http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index_en.htm>. Herman Miller will cooperate with the appropriate EU DPAs during investigation and resolution of complaints concerning human recourses data.

Please also note that if your complaint is not resolved through these channels, under limited circumstances, a binding arbitration option may be available before a Privacy Shield Panel.

Under the Privacy Shield frameworks, Herman Miller is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives as well as any such data that it provides to its third-party service providers and/or agents. Any personal information received under the Privacy Shield that we transfer to a third party must also comply with our Privacy Shield obligations, and we will be liable under the Privacy Shield for any failure to do so by the third party unless we prove that we are not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage.
